Preliminary Inventory to the Edward Taborsky Papers, 1938-1956.
Hoover Institution Archives
Edward Taborsky Papers
1938-1956
82087
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes (4.2 linear feet)
Diaries, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, and correspondence, relating to Edvard Benes and to Czechoslovak politics and foreign relations, 1938-1948, especially during World War II.
Taborsky, Edward.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Czechoslovak diplomat; personal aide to President Edvard Beneš, 1939-1945; minister to Sweden, 1945-1948.
Scope and Contents note
Diaries, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, and correspondence, relating to Edvard Beneš and to Czechoslovak politics and foreign relations, 1938-1948, especially during World War II.
Benes, Edvard, 1884-1948.; Czechoslovakia--Foreign relations--Sweden.; Czechoslovakia--History--1938-1945.; Czechoslovakia--History--Coup d'état, 1948.; Czechoslovakia.; Sweden--Foreign relations--Czechoslovakia.; Sweden.; World War, 1939-1945--Czechoslovakia.; World War, 1939-1945.
- FOLDER, unrestricted as of April 1983
  - Folder (Box 1)
- DIARIES, 1938-1949
  - 1938-1940 (published) (Box 1)
  - 1941 (unpublished; photocopies)
  - 1942-1945 (unpublished; photocopies) (Box 2)
  - 1945-1949 (Sweden and United States; unpublished; originals)
- CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1938-1956. Assorted documents
  - 1938 (Box 3)
  - 1939-1944, excerpts compiled by Edward Taborsky
  - 1939-1945, exact dates uncertain
  - 1939
  - 1940
  - 1941
  - 1942
  - 1943 (Box 4)
  - 1944
  - 1945
  - 1945-1956
- SUBJECT FILE
  - Benes, Edward (Box 4)
    - Contacts with Holy See
    - Mackenzie (Compton) biography. Materials for, 1944
    - Messages to Czechoslovakia from Benes, 1939-1944 (Box 5)
    - Speeches and articles by Benes, 1939-1944
  - Czechoslovakia
    - Government-in-exile. Official gazette, 1940-1944
    - Relations with France
    - Relations with Great Britain and British dominions, 1939-1945 (Box 6)
    - Relations with Poland
    - Relations with the Soviet Union (Box 7)
    - Relations with the United States, 1939-1945
    - Reorganization after liberation
    - State Council (Box 8)
  - Hodza, Milan
  - Jaksch, Wenzel
  - Osusky, Stefan
  - Population transfers. Study by Edward Taborsky
  - Slovak affairs
- REPORTS
  - From Czechoslovakia, 1939-1944, by Czechoslovak underground groups (Box 9)
  - From Germany, 1939-1944, mainly by Czechoslovak intelligence agents
  - From Turkey, Sweden, Switzerland, Hungary, and elsewhere, 1939-1944